JASON MANGIN

LOCATION: Salt Lake City, UT 84108 LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/jason-mangin

PHONE: (843)437-5934 GITHUB: www.github.com/Jollyrgr83

EMAIL: jasongmangin@gmail.com PORTFOLIO: https://jollyrgr83.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Thorough and meticulous Full Stack Web Developer applying engineering background and strong technical skills towards building dynamic and effective full stack applications. Strategic problem-solver with the persistence necessary to execute goals. Prolific communicator with diverse background in engineering, operations, consulting, and high-intensity environments. Experienced with multiple languages, databases, and platforms including JavaScript, React, SQL, Mongo, Node, SalesForce, and Cornerstone.

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Mongo Frameworks: React, Node, Bootstrap, ¡Query

Core Concepts: MERN, Database, Leadership, Communication

PROJECTS

Rodeo Scoring Database

Repo: https://github.com/Jollyrgr83/rodeo-scoring-version-2 | Link: https://rodeo-scoring-version-2.herokuapp.com/

- This project was developed to assist a public power utility (or similar entity) in facilitating an annual lineworkers rodeo (or similar competition). It uses jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, Node.js, and Express to allow users to enter competitor, event, competition tier, and score info and generate necessary reports for standings, results, and pdfs.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, Node, Express

Bier Run

Repo: https://github.com/Jollyrgr83/bierRun | Link: https://bier-run.herokuapp.com/

- This project was developed as a method for licensed beer vendors to perform home beer delivery after the
 passage of Utah Bill HB 203. It is a MERN stack allowing customers to place beer delivery orders and
 vendors to fulfill them. Bier Run utilizes Auth0 for registration and login.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node, Express, Passport

EXPERIENCE

Independent Consultant

Charleston, SC and Salt Lake City, UT

2018 - Present

Assisted small to midsize companies in various aspects of Learning and Development and Organizational Management including:

- Gap analysis followed by program development and implementation
- Organizational development, change management, learning content creation and delivery
- Implementation, operation, and optimization of business software including Saba, Cornerstone, SalesForce, Lectora, and Articulate
- Communication between and at several levels including C-suite

Supervisor Learning and Development, South Carolina Public Service Authority

Moncks Corner, SC 2016 - 2018

Supervised the scheduling, content, and delivery of all required training for over 1700 personnel in multiple areas of operation and expertise.

• Effectively managed a training budget in excess of one million dollars and reduced costs by 50% in the first three months.

- Conducted a comprehensive overhaul of existing Environmental, Safety, and Health training to ensure effectiveness and compliance with current standards
- Directly supervised a team of 8 direct reports in separate geographical areas that successfully met all training requirements using multiple delivery methods
- Conducted a comprehensive upgrade to the Saba Learning Management System, including training system administrators and a comprehensive overhaul to existing training assignments, content, and rule structures

Nuclear Submarine Officer, United States Navy

Various Locations 2008 - 2016

Extensive experience in various areas related to the operation, maintenance, and training of Naval Nuclear Power Platforms:

• Department Manager

- Reporting directly to the Chief Executive responsible for the planning, operation, and requirements associated with maintenance, water chemistry, and radiological controls including auditing and surveillance, strategic planning and leadership, project planning and supervision, and quality assurance and auditing
- Directly supervised 1 3 direct reports with indirectly reporting teams of 5 10

Shift Manager

- Reporting directly to the Chief Executive responsible for the training, operation, and maintenance associated with a naval nuclear power plant on a rotating shift schedule. Conducted various personnel administration, coaching, and other duties including conflict resolution, and team development in a complex and high-pressure environment with cross-functional teams.
- \circ Directly supervised 10 12 direct reports with indirectly reporting teams of 30 50. Additionally, supervised the training and qualification of 30 50 trainees.

Team Leader

- Responsible to the Department Manager for the operation, maintenance, training, and development
 of the team responsible for the maintenance and operation of a particular aspect of nuclear
 submarine operations
- Directly supervised 1 2 direct reports with 5 10 indirect reports. Watch leader for a team of 11 direct reports responsible for the operation and maintenance of a naval nuclear power plant in various operational periods including routine, complex maintenance, and casualty response.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining skills to design and build dynamic end-to-end web applications using HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Database Theory, and more.

B.S. Applied Mathematics: Auburn University, Auburn, AL

Degree focused on mathematical modeling, system optimization, cryptography, and algorithms.

Naval Nuclear Power Program: Various Locations

A high-intensity, fast-paced training program focusing on topics related to the nuclear, mechanical, electrical, and chemical theory, design, troubleshooting, operation, and leadership necessary to safely operate Naval Nuclear Power Plants.